Vendy C Prum

vendyprum@gmail.com | (408) 550-5583 | LinkedIn | Portfolio | GitHub

SUMMARY

I am a full stack web developer proficient in JavaScript, React, and Node.js. I have over 4 years of experience as a Quality Engineer at Fitbit, which has allowed me to develop my failure analysis skills, communicational skills, and the ability to work as a team player.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Enzyme, Jest, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Back-end: Node.js, Mocha & Chai, RESTful APIs **Dev Tools:** Git, GitHub, Chrome Dev Tools, Heroku

WORK EXPERIENCE

Fitbit, Inc – Quality Engineer

May 2016 - January 2020

- Led team of engineers for troubleshooting component-level failure analysis on class II medical devices in order to drive towards corrective actions
- Analyzed defective class II medical devices to determine the root cause of failures in order to improve the manufacturing process and prevent future failures
- Worked cross-functionally with hardware, firmware, and regulatory compliance teams to implement corrective and preventive actions in order to eliminate the probability of receiving non-conformities during audits

Fitbit, Inc - Engineering Technician

November 2015 - May 2016

- Executed manufacturing, battery, water leak, and visual inspection tests on new and existing products in order to improve product quality
- Assisted Quality Engineers with complaint handling and medical device reporting to remain compliant with section 820.198 of FDA 21 CFR – Part 820 Regulations

Lattice Semiconductor – Silicon Architecture Engineer Intern

June 2015 - September 2015

PROJECTS

Animal Crossing: Museum Donation Tracker

- GitHub: Client Repo | Server Repo
- Built a companion app for Animal Crossing New Horizons, which allows users to keep track of their items donated to the museum
- Skills used: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, Node.js, Express, Mocha & Chai, RESTful APIs

Clear Mind: Minfulness Journaling

- GitHub: Client Repo | Server Repo
- Role in 5-member team: Product Manager, Frontend Lead, and Design Lead
- Built frontend of journaling application, which allowed users to keep track of daily tasks, record inner thoughts, encourage mindful acts, and track sleep and emotional patterns
- Skills used: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, Node.js, Express, Mocha & Chai, RESTful APIs

EDUCATION

THINKFUL (Engineering Immersion)

February 2020 - June 2020

- Learned industry best practices and practical software development standards with a focus on HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, React, and algorithms & data structures
- Created and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks by collaborating several hours every week with a senior web developer

University of California, Santa Cruz

September 2012 - March 2016

• BS Electrical Engineering